Guide to the Wells Fargo Steinbeck Collection, 1892-1981
Department of Special Collections
- Series 12. John Steinbeck Books and Articles
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. Tortilla Flat / by John Steinbeck; illustrated by Ruth Gannett. New York: Covici-Friede, c1935. 316, [317] p.: ill.; 20 cm., First edition, cloth issue. Library of the Steinbeck Family book label on front paste-down.Top edge stained blue and trimmed, front and bottom edges rough trimmed. Goldstone, A4b.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. Tortilla Flat / by John Steinbeck; illustrated by Ruth Gannett. New York: Covici-Friede, c1935. 316, [317] p.: ill.; 20 cm., Signed by the author and Esther Rodgers on front free endpaper. Top edge stained blue and trimmed, front and bottom edges rough trimmed. Goldstone, A4b.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. Tortilla Flat / by John Steinbeck; illustrated by Ruth Gannett. New York: Covici-Friede, c1935. 316, [317] p.: ill.; 20 cm., First edition, cloth issue. Signed by the author and "Esther Rodgers 1935" on front free endpaper. Top edge stained blue and trimmed, front and bottom edges rough trimmed. Goldstone, A4b.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. In dubious battle / by John Steinbeck. New York: Covici-Friede Publishers, c1936. 349 p. 21 cm., First edition, regular issue. Signed by the author on front free endpaper. Library of the Steinbeck Family book label on front paste-down. Goldstone, A5b.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. In dubious battle / by John Steinbeck. New York: Covici-Friede Publishers, c1936. 349 p. 21 cm., Dust jacket chipped at head of spine. Goldstone, A5b.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. In dubious battle / John Steinbeck. New York: Published by The Viking Press, c1963. [6], 313 p. 20 cm. Compass Books; C132., 1963 Paperback edition. Goldstone, A5n.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. Of mice and men / John Steinbeck. New York: Covici-Friede Publishers, c1937. 186 p. 19 cm., First edition, first issue. Page 9, lines 20-21: includes "and only moved because the heavy hands were | pendula." Page 88, includes bullet between 8s of page number. Top edges stained. Inscribed on front free endpaper "For Esther and Caroll | with love | John"
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. Of mice and men / John Steinbeck. New York: Covici-Friede Publishers, c1937. 186 p. 19 cm., First issue. Page 9, lines 20-21: includes "and only moved because the heavy hands were | pendula." Page 88, includes bullet between 8s of page number. Top edges stained. Affixed to front turn-in of dust jacket, a newspaper clipping about Steinbeck having "never seen a performance of his 'Of Mice and Men.'" Signed by the author and Esther Rodgers on front free endpape
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. The red pony / by John Steinbeck; with illustrations by Wesley Dennis. New York: Viking Press, 1945. 131, [1] p.: col. ill.; 25 cm., First illustrated edition. "This edition is produced in full compliance with all war production board conservation orders." Variant with coarse beige buckram in blue-grey paperboard case; with Kipe Offset Process Company imprint on copyright page. Inscribed on half-title: "For Esther with love | John." Goldstone, A9c.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. The red pony / by John Steinbeck; with illustrations by Wesley Dennis. New York: Viking Press, 1945. 131, [1] p.: col. ill.; 25 cm., First illustrated edition. "This edition is produced in full compliance with all war production board conservation orders." Has Kipe offset and H. Wolff on copyright page. Signed by the author on front free endpaper. Library of the Steinbeck Family book label on verso front free endpaper, opposite half-title. Wanting blue-gray publisher's paperboard case. Goldstone, A9c.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. "Their blood is strong" / by John Steinbeck. San Francisco, Calif.: Simon J. Lubin Society of California, Inc., 1938. [iv], 33, [3] p.: ill.; 23 cm., First edition, fourth issue. Printed wrappers. Goldstone, A10d.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. The long valley / John Steinbeck. New York: The Viking Press, 1938. 303 p.; 21 cm., First edition. Cloth, dust jacket. Inscribed on title-page, "To Esther and Carroll | with love | John" Goldstone, Alla.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. The long valley / John Steinbeck. New York: The Viking Press, 1938. 303 p.; 21 cm., Contents: The chrysanthemums -- The white quail -- Flight -- The snake -- Breakfast -- The raid -- The harness -- The vigilante -- Johnny Bear -- The murder -- St. Katy the Virgin -- The red pony -- The leader of the people. Signature of Carolee Rodgers on front free endpaper. Price clipped from dust jacket. Goldstone, Alla.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. The grapes of wrath / John Steinbeck. 1st ed. New York: The Viking Press, 1939. 619 p.; 21 cm., First edition. Inscribed on lining page: "For Esther on her birthday | with love | John" Goldstone, A12a.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. The grapes of wrath / John Steinbeck. 1st ed. New York: The Viking Press, 1939. 619 p.; 21 cm., First edition. Signed by the author and Esther Rodgers on lining page. Goldstone, A12a.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. The grapes of wrath / John Steinbeck. 1st ed. New York: The Viking Press, 1939. 619 p.; 21 cm., Signed by Esther Rodgers on lining page. Goldstone, A12a.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. The forgotten village: with 136 photographs from the film of the same name / by Rosa Harvan Kline and Alexander Hackensmid; story by John Steinbeck. New York: The Viking Press, 1941. 143 p.: ill.; 26 cm., First edition. Inscribed on front free endpaper: "For Esther | with love | John" Goldstone, A14a.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. Sea of Cortez: a leisurely journal of travel and research, with a scientific appendix comprising materials for a source book on the marine animals of the Panamic faunal province / by John Steinbeck and Edward F. Ricketts. New York: The Viking Press, 1941. x, 598 p., [40] p. of plates: ill. (some col.), maps; 24 cm., First edition, issued in cloth. Signed on half-title page: ""For Esther | with love | John" Goldstone, A15b.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. Sea of Cortez: a leisurely journal of travel and research, with a scientific appendix comprising materials for a source book on the marine animals of the Panamic faunal province / by John Steinbeck and Edward F. Ricketts. New York: The Viking Press, 1941. x, 598 p., [40] p. of plates: ill. (some col.), maps; 24 cm., First edition, issued in cloth. Signed by Esther Rodgers on front free endpaper. Signed by the author on title-page. Library of the Steinbeck Family book label on front paste-down. Goldstone, A15b.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. Sea of Cortez: a leisurely journal of travel and research, with a scientific appendix comprising materials for a source book on the marine animals of the Panamic faunal province / by John Steinbeck and Edward F. Ricketts. New York: The Viking Press, 1941. x, 598 p., [40] p. of plates: ill. (some col.), maps; 24 cm., Signed by Esther Rodgers on front free endpaper. Goldstone, A15b.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. The log from the Sea of Cortez: the narrative portion of the book, Sea of Cortez, by John Steinbeck and E. F. Ricketts, 1941, here reissued with a profile "About Ed Ricketts" / by John Steinbeck. New York: The Viking Press, c1951. lxvii, [3], 282, [2] p., [2] leaves of plates: col. map (on lining paper), ports.; 22 cm., Second edition. Inscribed on half-title page: "For Esther with love, | John" Goldstone, A15c.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. The log from the Sea of Cortez: the narrative portion of the book, Sea of Cortez, by John Steinbeck and E. F. Ricketts, 1941, here reissued with a profile "About Ed Ricketts" / by John Steinbeck. New York: The Viking Press, c1951. lxvii, [3], 282, [2] p., [2] leaves of plates: col. map (on lining paper), ports.; 22 cm., First edition. Goldstone, A15c.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. The moon is down: a novel / by John Steinbeck. New York: The Viking Press, 1942. 188 p. 19 cm., First edition issue in cloth. "First published in March 1942." Inscribed on front free endpaper: "For Esther | with love | John" Large period on page 112 between "talk" and "this." Verso of title page is blank. Goldstone, A16b.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. The moon is down: a novel / by John Steinbeck. New York: The Viking Press, 1942. 188 p. 19 cm., First edition. "First published in March 1942." Signed by Esther Rodgers on front free endpaper. Signed by the author on front free endpaper. Library of the Steinbeck Family book label on front free endpaper. Large period on page 112 between "talk" and "this." Verso of title page is blank. Goldstone, A16b.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. The moon is down: a novel / by John Steinbeck. New York: The Viking Press, 1942. 188 p. 19 cm., "First published in March 1942." Signed by Esther Rodgers on front free endpaper. Large period on page 112 between "talk" and "this." Verso of title page is blank. Goldstone, A16b.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. Bombs away: the story of a bomber team / written for the United States Army Air Forces by John Steinbeck; with 60 photographs by John Swope. New York: The Viking Press, 1942. 184, [185], [7] p.: ill.; 22 cm., First edition. On verso of t.p.: First published by The Viking Press in November 1942. On prelim. leaf list of author's works. Inscribed on front free endpaper: "For Esther | with love | John" Goldstone, A18a.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. Bombs away: the story of a bomber team / written for the United States Army Air Forces by John Steinbeck; with 60 photographs by John Swope. New York: The Viking Press, 1942. 184, [185], [7] p.: ill.; 22 cm., First edition. On verso of title page: First published by The Viking Press in November 1942. On prelim. leaf list of author's works. Library of the Steinbeck Family book label on front paste-down. Signed by the author and Esther Rodgers on front free endpaper. Goldstone, A18a.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. Bombs away: the story of a bomber team / written for the United States Army Air Forces by John Steinbeck; with 60 photographs by John Swope. New York: The Viking Press, 1942. 184, [185], [7] p.: ill.; 22 cm., Signed by Esther Rodgers on front free endpaper. Goldstone, A18a.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. Steinbeck / selected by Pascal Covici. New York: The Viking Press, 1943. viii, 568p. 17cm. The Viking portable library., First edition. "Paul Elder & Co., San Francisco" book label on rear paste-down. Inscribed "Carolee Rodgers" on front free endpaper. Goldstone, A19a.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. [Selections. 1971] The portable Steinbeck / Revised, selected, and introduced by Pascal Covici, Jr. New York: The Viking Press [1971] xlii, 692 p. 19 cm.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. [Selections. 1946] The portable Steinbeck / selected by Pascal Covici. Enlarged edition With an introduction by Lewis Gannett. New York: The Viking press, 1946. xxx, 609 p. 17 cm. The Viking portable library., Inscribed "Esther Rodgers" on front free endpaper. Goldstone, A19b.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. Cannery Row / by John Steinbeck. New York: The Viking Press, 1945. 208 p. 20 cm., First edition, issue in cloth. "This edition was produced in full compliance with all War Production Board Conservation Orders" "First published by The Viking Press in January 1945." Inscribed on front free endpaper: "For Esther & Carroll | from their brother | John Steinbeck" Goldstone, A22a.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. Cannery Row / by John Steinbeck. New York: The Viking Press, 1945. 208 p. 20 cm., "This edition was produced in full compliance with all War Production Board Conservation Orders." "First published by The Viking Press in January 1945." Signed by Esther Rodgers on front free endpaper. Goldstone, A22a.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. The wayward bus / John Steinbeck. New York: The Viking Press, 1947. 312 p.; 21 cm., First edition. Signed by the author on front free endpaper. Library of the Steinbeck Family book label on front paste-down. "Published by the Viking Press in February 1947." Goldstone, A23a.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. The wayward bus / John Steinbeck. New York: The Viking Press, 1947. 312 p.; 21 cm., Signed by Esther Rodgers on front free endpaper. Goldstone, A23a.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. The wayward bus / John Steinbeck. New York: The Viking Press, 1947. 312 p.; 21 cm., First edition. Inscribed on front free endpaper: "For Esther with love | John S" Goldstone, A23a.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. The wayward bus / John Steinbeck. New York: The Viking Press, 1947. 312 p.; 21 cm., Book of the Month Club. Wanting dust jacket. Signed by Esther Rodgers on front free endpaper. Goldstone, A23a.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. The pearl / John Steinbeck; with drawings by José Clemente Orozco. New York: The Viking Press, 1947. 122 p.: ill.; 21 cm., First edition. Second printing. Inscribed on front free endpaper: "For Esther with love | from | John" Goldstone, A25a.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. The pearl / John Steinbeck; with drawings by José Clemente Orozco. New York: The Viking Press, 1947. 122 p.: ill.; 21 cm., First edition. Signed by the author on front free endpaper. Goldstone, A25a.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. The pearl / John Steinbeck; with drawings by José Clemente Orozco. New York: The Viking Press, 1947. 122 p.: ill.; 21 cm., Goldstone, A25a.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. A Russian journal / John Steinbeck; with pictures by Robert Capa. New York: The Viking Press, 1948. [3], 220 p. illus. 26 cm., First edition. Price clipped on dust jacket. Library of the Steinbeck Family book label on inside paste-down. Goldstone, A27a.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. A Russian journal / John Steinbeck; with pictures by Robert Capa. New York: The Viking Press, 1948. [3], 220 p. illus. 26 cm., First edition. Goldstone, A27a.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. Burning bright: a play in story form / John Steinbeck. New York: The Viking Press, 1950. 159 p. 19 cm., Goldstone, A29a.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. Burning bright: a play in story form / John Steinbeck. New York: The Viking Press, 1950. 159 p. 20 cm., First edition. Inscribed on front free endpaper: "For Esther | With love | John"
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. The short novels of John Steinbeck: Tortilla Flat, The red pony, Of mice and men, The moon is down, Cannery Row, The pearl / John Steinbeck; with an introduction by Joseph Henry Jackson. New York: The Viking Press, 1953. xiii, 407 p. 22 cm., First edition. Goldstone, A30a.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. East of Eden / John Steinbeck. New York: The Viking Press, 1952. [viii], 602 p. 22 cm., First edition, limited issue. On free endpaper: "This autographed first edition of East of Eden is limited to fifteen hundred copies, of which seven hundred and fifty are for private distribution." "John Steinbeck" in manuscript. Wanting glassine wrapper. In publisher's brown paperboard case. Goldstone, A32a.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. East of Eden / John Steinbeck. New York: The Viking Press, 1952. 602 p. 22 cm., First trade edition. Inscribed on front free endpaper: "Esther with all the love | John" Goldstone, A32b.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. East of Eden / John Steinbeck. New York: The Viking Press, 1952. 602 p. 22 cm., Dust jacket taped and chipped. Goldstone, A32b.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. Sweet Thursday / John Steinbeck. New York: The Viking Press, 1954. x, 273 p. 21 cm., Cloth, issue. "First published by the Viking Press in June 1954." Signed by the author on front free endpaper Library of the Steinbeck Family book label on front paste-down. References: Goldstone A33b.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. Sweet Thursday / John Steinbeck. New York: The Viking Press, 1954. x, 273 p. 21 cm., Cloth, dust jacket issue. "First published by the Viking Press in June 1954." Author's autograph card, signed by the author, affixed to front free endpaper. References: Goldstone A33b.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. Sweet Thursday / John Steinbeck. New York: The Viking Press, 1954. x, 273 p. 21 cm., Book Club Edition (printed on Front fold-down of dust jacket). Goldstone, A33f.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. The short reign of Pippin IV: a fabrication / John Steinbeck; drawings by William Pène du Bois. New York: The Viking Press, 1957. 188 p. illus. 21 cm., The Dedication Copy. Unique copy bound by Gerhard Gerlack in full turquoise crushed morocco, gilt rules on front cover; heraldic logo inlaid in red morocco at center of back cover; raised bands, gilt, three panels on spine in red morocco, gilt title, author's name in panels. All edges gilt. Preserved in slipcase with turquoise edges at opening, smooth tan buckram sides. Library of the Steinbeck Family book label on front paste-down. References: Not listed in Goldstone
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. The short reign of Pippin IV: a fabrication / John Steinbeck; drawings by William Pène du Bois. New York: The Viking Press, 1957. 188 p. illus. 21 cm., First edition. Inscribed on front free endpaper: "For Esther | with love | another edition | follows | John" Inscribed (in John Steinbeck's hand) on dedication page, "with all my love." Goldstone, A36a.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. The short reign of Pippin IV: a fabrication / John Steinbeck; drawings by William Pène du Bois. New York: The Viking Press, 1957. 188 p. illus. 21 cm., Inscribed in pencil on front free endpaper "Finney" Goldstone, A36a.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. Once there was a war / John Steinbeck. New York: The Viking Press, 1958. 233 p. 22 cm., First edition. Inscribed on front free endpaper: "To Sister Esther | from | John" Goldstone, A37a.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. The winter of our discontent / John Steinbeck. New York: The Viking Press, 1961. 311 p.; 22 cm., First edition, limited issue. "The first edition of | THE | WINTER | OF OUR | DISCONTENT | limited to 500 copies | has been specially printed and bound | for friends of the author and the publishers" appears in place of half-title Inscribed "For Esther | with love | from | John" on front free endpaper. Goldstone, A38a.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. The winter of our discontent / John Steinbeck. New York: The Viking Press, 1961. 311 p.; 22 cm., "Second Printing Before Publication" on printer's imprint. Goldstone, A38b
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. The winter of our discontent / John Steinbeck. New York: The Viking Press, 1961. 311 p.; 22 cm., First trade edition. Signed by the author on front free endpaper. Library of the Steinbeck Family book label on front paste-down. "Second printing before publication" on printer's imprint. Goldstone, A38b.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. Travels with Charley: in search of America / [by] John Steinbeck. New York: The Viking Press, [1962] 246 p. 22 cm., First edition. Signed on half-title page: "For Esther | with love | from | John and Charley" Goldstone, A39a.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. Travels with Charley: in search of America / [by] John Steinbeck. New York: The Viking Press, [1962] 246 p. 22 cm., Goldstone, A39a.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. Travels with Charley; in search of America / [by] John Steinbeck. New York: The Viking Press, 1962. 246 p. 22 cm., Signed by Esther Rodgers on lining page. Goldstone, A39a.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. Speech accepting the Nobel prize for literature, Stockholm, December 10, 1962. New York: Viking Press, [1962 or 1963]. 10, [2] p.: port.; 23 cm., Folded paper covers. Inscribed: "For my sister Esther with love from John." Frontispiece photograph of JS. Page 10, last word "man" corrected with pen "men J.S." "Three thousand two hundred copies have been printed for friends of the author and the publisher by the Meriden Gravure Company [Meriden, Conn.] and the Spiral Press [New York] in Emerson type on Mohawk Superfine paper" T.p. verso. Inscribed on verso of half-title: "For my sister Esther | with love | from | John" Includes holographic correction by Steinbeck, page 10, changes last word from "man" to "men J.S." Tan paper wrappers. "Books by John Steinbeck": p.[11]
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. America and Americans / Text by John Steinbeck; Photographs edited by the staff of Studio Books, the Viking Press. New York: The Viking Press, [1966]. 207 p. illus. (part col.) map (on lining papers) 28 cm., First edition. Inscribed on front paste-down: "For | Esther | from | John | Steinbeck" References: Goldstone, A43a.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. America and Americans / Text by John Steinbeck; Photographs edited by the staff of Studio Books, the Viking Press. New York: The Viking Press, [1966]. 207 p. illus. (part col.) map (on lining papers) 28 cm., Goldstone, A43a.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. America and Americans / Text by John Steinbeck; Photographs edited by the staff of Studio Books, the Viking Press. New York: The Viking Press, [1966]. 207 p. illus. (part col.) map (on lining papers) 28 cm., Signed by the author on front free endpaper. Library of the Steinbeck Family book label on front free endpaper. Goldstone, A43a.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. Journal of a novel: the East of Eden letters / [by] John Steinbeck. New York: The Viking Press, [1969]. ix, 182 p., [7] folded leaves of plates ill. (some col.), facsims. 29 cm., First edition, limited issue. Viking Press insignia on Half-title. On verso of half-title: "This first edition of | Journal of a Novel: The East of Eden Letters | by John Steinbeck | with facsimiles of seven pages from the | manuscript and a page from the original | dedication, is limited to 600 copies." Blue boards, blue quarter cloth spine, stamped in silver. Glassine chipped. Publisher's blue case with blue paper label. Library of the Steinbeck Family book label on free endpaper. Goldstone, A44a.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. Journal of a novel: the East of Eden letters / [by] John Steinbeck. New York: The Viking Press, [1969]. ix, 182 p. facsims. (on lining papers) 22 cm., "First published in 1969 in a limited edition of 1000 copies and simultaneously in its present format" on printer's imprint page. Dust jacket torn. Goldstone, A44b.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. Journal of a novel: the East of Eden letters / [by] John Steinbeck. New York: The Viking Press, [1969]. ix, 182 p. facsims. (on lining papers) 22 cm., "First published in 1969 in a limited edition of 1000 copies and simultaneously in its present format" on printer's imprint page. Goldstone, A44b.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. Journal of a novel: the East of Eden letters / [by] John Steinbeck. New York: The Viking Press, [1969]. ix, 182 p. facsims. (on lining papers) 22 cm., "First published in 1969 in a limited edition of 1000 copies and simultaneously in its present format" on printer's imprint page. Goldstone, A44b.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. Journal of a novel: the East of Eden letters / [by] John Steinbeck. New York: Viking Press [1969] ix, 182 p. facsims. (on lining papers) 22 cm, Signed by Esther Rodgers on lining page. Price clipped on dust jacket. "First published in 1969 in a limited edition of 1000 copies and simultaneously in its present format" on printer's imprint page. Goldstone, A44b.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. Two Letters in Facsimile (to Carl Wilhelmson). The Imprint: the publication of the Associates of the Stanford University Libraries. [Stanford, Calif.]: Associates of the Stanford University Libraries. Vol. 1, no. 1 (Apr. 1975). 24 p.: ill.; 26 cm., 10-15. [2 copies]
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. [Malory, Thomas, Sir, 15th cent.]. The acts of King Arthur and his noble knights: from the Winchester Manuscripts of Thomas Malory and other sources / John Steinbeck; edited by Chase Horton. New York: Farrar, Straus and Giroux, c1976. xiii, 363 p.; 24 cm., First edition.